Hello, my friends, and welcome to exercise number 14.
We are asked to find the time and complexity of the method Factorial Victoria is returning, type is
integer and it has a perimeter end and so holds the video and think about this for 10 seconds and write
down the solution on paper.
Or and comment in the comments below.
So I am waiting your comments, and I hope you like solve it and you understand the algorithm and how
to solve this time of complexity questions.
So let's begin.
And above we have if and if and deaths, as we said in the in the general rules of the big own notation,
we took the worst one in the F conditions.
So if else?
If else, if and else, we are having three three like possibilities or three switches, if else if
and.
Three cases.
So we took the worst one.
We start studying with the first one.
If and less than zero, it's comparing return minus one.
It was all of one because nothing is doing and nothing is done here with a complex hour, depending
on their impact here else, if an equal equal to one return one.
Also, it is of one because there is no interference or dependence on their input that we have.
As her return and times factorial and minus one, this is a straight, it is straight research.
We will learn about recursion in their next videos, so don't worry.
This is dedication.
This is the calling of the function again, going up here and call the function again and again.
But here we are passing and minus one.
OK, so every time it is increased, decreased by one.
And here it is, and times factorial one minus one.
This is the this is depending on there and value.
So if we pass factor of five return five times factorial of four.
So this will depend on the and value.
OK, let's take an example if we pass and equal to five, so.
And equal to five.
This will result if analysts and zero no, as if an equal equal to one no else return and return, this
is their return.
The first statement five, which is n times factorial go and call factorial.
Off for.
So again, it go and execute this factorial offer would be and less than zero no equal to one no else
and equal to return and times factorial.
So it returns for time factorial of three.
Factorial of three.
It will go up again.
Make check with less than zero equal to zero to one.
Or less there or else return and times factorial of two.
So three times factorial of two.
Again, three times factor of two to a factor of two less than zero, no LCF equal equal to one, no
return in two times.
Factorial of one.
It is.
Here it is two times a factor of one factor of one going up less than zero, no equal equal to one.
Yes, so return one, so factor of one is one.
And this is the.
We will see this in the next videos in more and more details.
So don't worry.
Just understand this exercise.
No one is substituted, but here.
One.
So two times the one is equal to do now, do is again executed and substituted here.
So three times two is equal to six.
Factorial of three is equal to six.
So six is executed, substituted here six times.
Four is equal to 24.
OK.
Two factorial of four, this is the factor of four factorial four is executed here, self returned five
times factorial of four, which is one 20, I think.
Yes, there's one 20.
OK.
It's very simple.
So we return one 20 if we pass and equal to five, the value of this function or the returning value,
it returned one 20.
So it depends on the factory, but since it is a straightforward recursion, it is depending on the
the end.
OK.
So it will result in.